Blumen, Isadore, Papers /4138
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Isadore Blumen Papers
1970-1992
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Blumen, Isadore
/4138
1.11 cubic feet
1.1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Correspondence, files, and publications from the University Centers for Rational Alternatives and from the Cornell Committee on Special Education Projects (COSEP).
8016828
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, October 26, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 01, 2019
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, files, and publications from the University Centers for Rational Alternatives. This material deals especially with the unrest on the Cornell Ithaca campus in 1968-1969. Also includes material from the Cornell Committee on Special Education Projects (COSEP), focuses on the screening process for applicants to the program. A cassette tape contains Professor Blumen's explanation of the files.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3006: ILR School Dean's Office Publications /4135 OHT: ILR School Founding Faculty Oral History Project /4225: Isadore Blumen Files /4297: ILR School Biography Files 6047: Archives Information File
Blumen, Isadore.
8016828
- Fresno City College (letter, news clippings) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- MEASURE: no.80-81, 84, 105 (1989-1992) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Office Management and Budget - memo #73-17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- In the Supreme Court of the State of Washington (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cornell Daily Sun - news clippings - Sept. 25, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- People v. Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cornell's United Religious Program (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cornell (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bower, John (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Univ. Centers for Rational Alternatives, Inc., 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- George H. Hildebrand, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Afro-American Studies (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alternate Bookstore (Box 1, Folder 13)
- AAUP (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Afro-American Soc. - W.S. Incident (Box 1, Folder 15)
- COSEP (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cornell Univ. - New Student Orientation Comm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- New York State Vegetable Growers News: v. XXIX, no. 2, Feb. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Misc. correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Ithaca College - visiting Professorship correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- COSEP Incident - Jan. 15, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Universities: 1970-71, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- COSEP, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- COSRP Workshop - June 17-19, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- FCR Meeting 4/1173, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Measure: no.63-65, 68, 71, 74, 76, 78-79, 83, 85-86, 88-100 (1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- University Centers for Rational Alternatives, Inc. - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 27)
- UCRA - Correspondence Before 12/70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Measure - no. 37, 40-48, 50-52, 54-60, 67, 73, 75, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Measure - Before 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- UCRA Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- UCRA Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- UCRA Correspondence Before 9/1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- UCRA Georgetown (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous clippings and notes (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Prof. Blumen - Tape of explanation of files (Box 2)